Guide to the James Rowland Angell Personal Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, (1874), 1880-1947, (1949-1850); Series II; 8.5 linear feet (22 Boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Dickson, William B., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 147A)
    - Downey, June E., 1893 (Box 16, Folder 147B)
    - Ducerter, H. Van, 1893 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Eliot, Charles W., 1893 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - The Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Fitchener, E.M., 1897 (Box 16, Folder 151)
      See also: box 21, folder 261
    - Fite, Warner, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Fordan, Elsie P., undated (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 153A)
    - Frankforter, J.B., 1894 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Gale, Harlow, 1894 (Box 17, Folder 155)
    - Gay, Edwin F., 1890-1891 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Genealogy of Angell Family, correspondence related to, 1929-1936 (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - Germany, 1893-1894 (Box 17, Folder 158)
      - includes: Ferber, Hans
      - includes: Kulpe, Oswald
      - includes: Liebisch, Bernhard
      - includes: Sack, Agnes
    - Glessner, J.J., 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - Goode, Patrick A., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 159A)
    - Graves, Frank Pierrepont, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 159B)
    - Great Britain, 1903-1936 (Box 17, Folder 160)
      - includes: Bosanquet, Bernard
      - includes: Lodge, Oliver
      - includes: Pringle-Pattison, A.S.
      - includes: Schiller, F.C.S.
      - includes: Royal Society of Arts
      - includes: Taggart, J. Ellis
    - Greene, Ed, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 161)
    - Greene, Jerome D., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 161A)
    - Greene, Jessie Rice, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 162)
    - Grove Street Cemetery Plot, 1931-1932 (Box 17, Folder 163)
    - Haff, D.J., 1892 (Box 17, Folder 164)
    - Harding, Susan G., 1898 (Box 17, Folder 165)
    - Hazard, Margaret R., 1892 (Box 17, Folder 166)
    - Henry Holt & Company, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 167)
    - Hodden, Alfred S., 1892-1896, undated (Box 17, Folder 168)
    - Hollzer, Judge H.A., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 168A)
    - Hough, Williston L., 1893-1894 (Box 17, Folder 169)
    - Howard, Anna H., 1892 (Box 17, Folder 170)
    - Hume, Edward H., 1943 (Box 17, Folder 171)
    - Hunsaker, Jerome C., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 171A)
    - Iddings, Joseph P., 1901 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - Illness, correspondence received and answeres by Mrs. Angell during Mr. Angell's recuperation, 1922, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 173)
    - James, William, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 174)
    - Jay, Pierre, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 174A)
    - Kappa Delta Pi, Executive Council, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 175)
    - Kaufmann, Charles, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 175A)
    - Kent School, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - Kinard, Margaret C., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 176A)
    - Kronovet, Milton, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 176B)
    - Landon, M.L., 1928 (Box 17, Folder 177)
    - Lape, Miss ____, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 177A)
    - Lloyd, Alfred, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 178)
    - Loos, B.F. & Company, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 179)
    - Lytle, T.G., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 179A)
    - McAlpin, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 180)
    - MacClintock, W.D., 1900 (Box 17, Folder 181)
    - McLennan, S.F., 1894 (Box 17, Folder 182)
    - Macmillan and Company, 1894 (Box 17, Folder 183)
    - Miller, Wilhelm, 1892 (Box 17, Folder 184)
    - Mitcheltree, Russell, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 184A)
    - Morris, Roger, 1892 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - Murchison, Carl, letters regarding biographical sketch of James Rowland Angell, 1929-1936 (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - National Academy of Sciences
      - Correspondence, 1922-1929 (Box 18, Folder 187)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1936 (Box 18, Folder 188)
      - Lists of officers, members, and foreign associates, 1924-1936 (Box 18, Folder 189)
      - Meetings: invitations, announcements, and programs, 1922-1937 (Box 18, Folder 190)
      - Abstracts of papers, Presidential address, 1933-1935 (Box 18, Folder 191)
      - Nominees; trust funds, 1929-1933 (Box 18, Folder 192)
    - National Broadcasting Company
      - Correpondence (with printed material), 1937-1944 (Box 19, Folder 193)
      - Microfilm; educational broadcasting, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 194)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (with printed material), 1920-1921 (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - National Institute of Social Science Gold Medal Award (with printed material), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 196)
    - National Recovery Act Broadcast (with copies of speeches and press clippings), 1933 (Box 19, Folder 197)
    - New England Historical Genealogical Society, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 198)
    - Northrop, Cyrus, 1894 (Box 19, Folder 199)
    - North Star Woolen Mill, 1894 (Box 19, Folder 200)
    - Noyes, Constance W., 1894 (Box 19, Folder 201)
    - Operation, letters received during recuperation, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 202)
    - Palmer, Bertha, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 203)
    - Peninsular State Bank, 1928-1929 (Box 19, Folder 204)
    - Permutit Company, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 205)
    - Personal Chronological File, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 206)
    - Personal Miscellaneous File, 1920-1921 (Box 19, Folder 207)
    - Peters, Lovett C., 1937 (Box 19, Folder 207A)
    - Phelps, Walter, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 208)
    - Pierce, A. H., 1893-1894 (Box 19, Folder 209)
    - Pinkham, P.L.S., 1891 (Box 19, Folder 210)
    - Post-mortem correspondence and tributes, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 211)
    - Press correspondence, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 212)
    - Prohibition, correspondence concerning, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 213)
    - Psychology, reaction to Mr. Angell's book, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 214)
    - Psychological Monographs
      - A-Y, 1914-1920 (Box 20, Folder 215)
      - Angier, Roswell P., 1914-1915 (Box 20, Folder 216)
      - Arps, George F., 1919-1920 (Box 20, Folder 217)
      - Bills, Marion A., 1919-1920 (Box 20, Folder 218)
      - Clopper, Edward N., 1914-1915 (Box 20, Folder 219)
      - Coover, J.E., 1915 (Box 20, Folder 220)
      - Crane, Harry W., 1913-1915 (Box 20, Folder 221)
      - Crosland, H.R., 1920 (Box 20, Folder 222)
      - Franz, Shepherd I., 1914-1920 (Box 20, Folder 223)
      - Gatewood, Esther L., 1919-1920 (Box 20, Folder 224)
      - Hull, Clark L., 1919-1920 (Box 20, Folder 225)
      - Langfeld, Herbert S., 1914 (Box 20, Folder 226)
      - Mitchell, David, 1914-1915 (Box 20, Folder 227)
      - Moore, Bruce, 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 228)
      - Moore, Thomas V., 1917-1920 (Box 20, Folder 229)
      - Munsterberg, Hugo, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 230)
      - Peterson, John C., 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 231)
      - Pintner, Rudolf, 1915-1920 (Box 20, Folder 232)
      - Seashore, C.E., 1921 (Box 20, Folder 233)
      - Snoddy, George S., 1919-1920 (Box 20, Folder 234)
    - Psychological Review Company
      - Warren, Howard C., President, 1914-1921 (Box 20, Folder 235)
      - Miscellaneous editorial correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 236)
    - Putnam, Alice H., 1897 (Box 21, Folder 237)
    - Quadrangle Club, 1914 (Box 21, Folder 238)
    - Ramsey, William B., 1891 (Box 21, Folder 239)
    - Raymond, Jerome H., 1894 (Box 21, Folder 240)
    - Requests for autographs of James Rowland Angell, 1930-1937 (Box 21, Folder 241)
    - Requests for photographs of James Rowland Angell, 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 242)
    - Richmond, Charles A., 1910 (Box 21, Folder 243)
    - Rockefeller Foundation: Laura Spellman Rockefeller Memorial
      - Correspondence, 1921-1928 (Box 21, Folder 244)
      - Memorandum of Hanover Conference, research program, reports, and notes, 1923-1925 (Box 21, Folder 245)
    - Rolfe, John C., 1892-1895 (Box 21, Folder 246)
    - Ryerson, Caroline H., 1909 (Box 21, Folder 247)
    - Schampel Steam and Hot Water Heating, 1901 (Box 21, Folder 248)
    - Schoejke, H.F., 1895 (Box 21, Folder 249)
    - Scott, Fred N., 1891-1892 (Box 21, Folder 250)
    - Seymour, George Dudley, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 251)
    - Sherill, Charles H., 1934 (Box 21, Folder 251A)
    - Sizer, Theodore, 1935-1936 (Box 21, Folder 251B)
    - Smith-Codd Detective Bureau, 1892 (Box 21, Folder 252)
    - Smith, Walter, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 253)
    - Socks, W.D., 1892 (Box 21, Folder 254)
    - Stern, Mrs. O.M., 1898 (Box 21, Folder 255)
    - Stimson, Rev. Henry A., 1928 (Box 21, Folder 256)
    - Stricker, Maude, 1892 (Box 21, Folder 257)
    - Switzerland, 1901-1910 (Box 21, Folder 258)
      - includes: Ambrosoli & Villa
      - includes: Unidentified telegram
    - Symons, J.E., 1894-1897 (Box 21, Folder 259)
    - Tarbill, F.B., 1901 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Titchener, E.B., 1891-1901 (Box 21, Folder 261)
      See also: box 16, folder 151
    - Tomlinson, C.P., 1937 (Box 21, Folder 261A)
    - Tuttle, Henry Emerson, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 261B)
    - United Editors' Association, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - University of Chicago (with guest list), 1894-1920 (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - The University Club, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 264)
    - University of Michigan, 1910-1919 (Box 21, Folder 265)
    - Van Valkenbergh, A.S., 1909 (Box 21, Folder 266)
    - Ward, Henry Baldwin, undated (Box 21, Folder 267)
    - Watson, John B., 1910 (Box 21, Folder 268)
    - Wells Fargo & Company Express, 1910 (Box 21, Folder 269)
    - Western Universities Club, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 270)
    - Weston, S.F., 1920 (Box 21, Folder 271)
    - The Wheeler House, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 272)
    - Wilmorth, May H., 1900 (Box 21, Folder 273)
    - Winslow, Mary D., 1893 (Box 21, Folder 274)
    - Winterbottom, A.J., 1922 (Box 21, Folder 275)
    - Yale University
      - Alumni Organization (with 30th annual report, 1919-1920), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 276)
      - Athletics (with newspaper clippings, 1894), 1921 (Box 22, Folder 277)
      - Aurelian Society
        - Correspondence, 1921-1935 (Box 22, Folder 278)
        - Elections, addresses, report, announcement, and invitations, 1922-1933 (Box 22, Folder 279)
      - Class of 1890 (with announcements, class notes and changes of address), 1921-1933 (Box 22, Folder 280)
      - The Club (with lists of hosts, members and acknowledgement cards), 1922-1937 (Box 22, Folder 281)
      - Commencement Invitations, 1920-1921 (Box 22, Folder 282)
      - The Dissenters (with membership lists), 1922-1932 (Box 22, Folder 283)
      - Dodge Lectures, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 284)
      - Election as Yale President, congratulatory letters
        - February 16-23, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 285)
        - February 24-28, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 286)
        - March 1-10, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 287)
        - March 11-29, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 288)
        - April-June, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 289)
        - James Rowland Angell's replies to congratulatory letters, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 290)
      - Inaugural Address, congratulatory letters, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 291)
      - President, Arthur Hadley, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 292)
      - Provost, Williston Walker, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 293)
      - Retirement from Yale
        - Correspondence regarding (with university news statement), 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 294)
        - Correspondence concerning the Alumni Day Address (with clippings), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 295)
        - Invitations and offers to be accepted upon retirement, 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 296)
        - Invitations to parties in honor of James Rowland Angell (with speeches in his honor), 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 297)
        - Personal tributes regarding Mr. Angell and his administration, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 298)
        - Miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 299)
      - Secretary, Anson Phelps Stokes, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 300)
        - Assistant Secretary, Minot A. Osborn, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 301)
      - Social Science Club (with schedules and member lists), 1921-1937 (Box 24, Folder 302)
      - Treasurer, George Parmly Day, 1924-1937 (Box 24, Folder 303)
      - Yale-in-China (with confidential lists), 1945-1947 (Box 24, Folder 304)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (with announcement from Sheffield Scientific School), 1920-1934 (Box 24, Folder 305)
    - Unidentified letters, 1892-1946 (Box 24, Folder 306)
- WRITINGS, 1891-1942; Series III; 2.5 linear feet (8 Boxes)
  James Rowland Angell's writings are arranged according to their specific type. The first in the series are the manuscripts of the thesis on imagery which he presented to the University of Michigan for a M.A. degree in philosophy in 1891 and the thesis on Kant, written in German, which he submitted to the University of Halle in 1895. An incomplete manuscript copy and a typescript copy of his book, Elements of Psychology, completed in 1904, are followed by a number of articles, including one he wrote as chairman of the National Research Council in 1920 and one which appeared in the American Journal of Sociology in 1941. A book review of Mr. Angell's Chapters from Modern Psychology (1912) from the Yale Review is included in this series as well as a review, written in French, of Mr. Angell's work, The Relation of Structural and Functional Psychology to Philosophy. Several of Mr. Angell's speeches from 1918 to 1942 are arranged in three groups as printed, typed, and incomplete. His scholarly notes, those used in the preparation of lectures and speeches, are presented separately from the miscellaneous notes found among his papers.
  - Theses
    - M.A. thesis (University of Michigan) "The Image-Making Function of the Mind with a Supplementary Essay on the Imagery of Poetry," 180 pages, 1891 (Box 25, Folder 307)
    - Ph.D. thesis (in German, University of Halle) "The Treatment of Freedom in Kant's Critique of Pure Reason Compared with that in the Critique of Practical Reason," 58 pages, 1895 (Box 25, Folder 308)
  - Book: Elements of Psychology, 1904
    - Manuscript, chapters 1-6 (Box 26, Folder 309)
    - Manuscript, chapters 7-12 (Box 26, Folder 310)
    - Manuscript, chapters 13, 20, 25 (Box 26, Folder 311)
    - Typescript, chapters 1-10 (Box 26, Folder 312)
    - Typescript, chapters 11-23 (Box 27, Folder 313)
  - Articles
    - 1920-1922 (Box 27A, Folder 314)
    - 1925-1929 (Box 27A, Folder 314A)
    - 1933-1941 (Box 27A, Folder 314B)
  - Book Reviews
    - Roswell B. Angier's review of Angell's Chapters from Modern Psychology in Yale Review, 2nd series, II (1912-1913), pages 378-380 (Box 28, Folder 315)
    - Theodore Ribot's review of Angell's The Relations of Structural and Functional Psychology, undated (Box 28, Folder 315)
  - Speeches
    - Printed speeches
      - 1918-1924 (Box 28, Folder 316)
      - 1925-1927 (Box 28, Folder 316A)
      - 1928-1931 (Box 28, Folder 317)
      - 1933 (Box 28, Folder 317A)
      - 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 317B)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 28A, Folder 317C)
      - 1939-1941 (Box 28A, Folder 317)
    - Inaugural address, 1921 (Box 28A, Folder 318)
    - Typed speeches
      - 1920-1922 (Box 28A, Folder 319)
      - 1923-1925 (Box 28A, Folder 320)
      - 1926 (Box 28A, Folder 321)
      - 1927-1929 (Box 28A, Folder 322)
    - Typed speeches, 1932-1937, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 323-329)
    - Typed speeches, undated (Box 30, Folder 330)
    - Excerpts and incomplete copies of speeches, undated (Box 30, Folder 331)
    - "Nation's Colleges Honor Gettysburg": Sound newsreel film of Angell's address at Gettysburg College, 1932 May 27 (Box 30, Folder 331A)
  - Notes (Box 30, Folder 332)
    - Notes for speeches, undated (Box 30, Folder 332)
    - Scholarly notes (with charts and map), undated (Box 30, Folder 333)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 334)
- PRINTED MATERIALS, 1891-1946; Series IV; 0.25
  These are arranged according to the origin of publication. The first three folders contain Yale material; they are followed by miscellaneous reprints, periodicals and announcements.
  - Yale Alumni Week, Vol. XXX (1921), Nos. 23, 24, 26; Vol. XXXI (1922), No. 40, 1921-1922 (Box 30, Folder 335)
  - Yale Inauguration and Harvard Commencement programs, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 336)
  - Announcements of academic activities of various universities and schools, 1891-1946 (Box 30, Folder 337)
  - Miscellaneous reprints, periodicals and announcements, 1943-1946 (Box 30, Folder 338)
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS AND PHOTOGRAPHS, 1921-1945; Series V; 0.25
  The vast number of newspaper clippings relate to Mr. Angell's inauguration as Yale's President. These are divided into mounted, unmounted and headline pages accompanied by the remainder of the paper. A smaller group of clippings from after 1921 are arranged together in a separate folder. Clippings from periodicals and numerous family and academic photographs complete the series.
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Mounted by Ivy Lee Agency, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 339)
    - Unmounted, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 340)
    - Unmounted, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 341)
    - Headlines (newspaper issues), 1921 (Box 31, Folder 342)
    - Unmounted, 1923-1945 (Box 31, Folder 343)
    - Clippings from periodicals, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 344)
  - Photographs (Box 31, Folder 345)
    General note
    (Add 6/9/83)
    - Miscellaneous photographs of James Rowland Angell's inauguration as President of Yale University and of his other activities, 1920-1921, undated (Box 31, Folder 345)
    - Autograph album of Sarah W. Sawyer containing photographs of the Angell family, 1861 (Box 31, Folder 346)
- OVERSIZE
  - Inaugural greetings (From Series I), 1921 (Box 32)
  - Two posters celebrating Angell's birthdays (Box 33)
- Additional Material, 1927-1936; Accession 1983-M-013
  This addition consists of copies of materials produced by two related organizations, the General Education Board and the Rockefeller Foundation. The provenance of these materials is not clear, but several factors suggest that the papers belonged to James R. Angell. The minutes which form the bulk of the papers cover only the years in which Angell served on the boards of these organizations, and the two reports, issued by committees on which he served, have his name penciled on them. More importantly, the one letter in the papers is addressed to Angell.
  The history and purpose of the General Education Board and the Rockefeller Foundation (and their relationship to two other Rockefeller foundations, the International Education Board and the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial) are explained in the report in folder 34. As this report explains, the late 1920s and early 1930s - the period covered by this addition - were a time of redefinition for these groups. In 1928 a new objective was defined. Thereafter the Rockefeller Foundation supported research projects in the social sciences, the natural sciences, the medical sciences, and the humanities, while the General Education Board also pursued additional objectives of its own: to promote the reorganization of "general education" in the United States; to promote research in child growth and development; to stimulate the use of investigative experience as an educational tool; and to improve the quality of higher education for women and blacks in the South and newer states. The minutes here document the implementation of these programs.
  In this addition, the General Education Board materials run from May 1927 to December 1934. James R. Angell was already a member and trustee before and throughout this period. He also served on the Executive Committee from October 1932 to December 1934; and on the committee which produced the report in folder 10.
  The Rockefeller Foundation materials begin in November 1928, when Angell was already a member and trustee, and end abruptly in March 1936, although Angell's involvement apparently continued longer. He became an alternate member of the Executive Committee in April 1932, and a member of it in October 1932.
  Some materials, especially the reports, have been annotated in pencil, presumably by Angell. Markers in some of the minutes indicate some of the discussions relevant to Yale; in particular, support for Robert M. Yerkes' anthropoid breeding station, and for Ross Granville Harrison's researches in experimental embryology.
  Further Rockefeller Foundation materials will be found in Series II of the Angell Papers; and further materials concerning both organizations will be found in Angell's presidential papers, YRG 2-A-14.
  - General Education Board
    - Minutes
      - Vols. XV-XVIII, 1927 May 9 - 1930 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
      - Vols. XIX-XXII, 1930 October 17 - 1934 April 12 (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
      - [Vol. XXIII], 1934 April 13 - December 13 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Report on a Study of American Education," with "Summaries of Reports on American Education" and a letter to J.R. Angell from Mark A. May, 1932 December (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Minutes
      - 1928 November 9 - 1931 April 15 (Box 4, Folder 11-16)
      - 1931 April 28 - 1933 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 17-24)
      - 1934 January 19 - 1935 December 11 (Box 6, Folder 25-32)
      - 1936 January 17 - March 26 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - "Report of the Committee on Appraisal and Plan,", 1934 December 11 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Additional Material, 1833-1951; Accession 1984-M-101; 1 paige box, 1 framed picture
  Received from: Katharine B. Woodman, 14 October 1983, 31 October 1983, and 15 November 1983
  - Correspondence - Incoming
    - 1919-1928 (Box 1)
    - 1930-1937 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1951 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing
    - 1912-1921, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - [James B. Angell?], 1857-1879 (Box 1)
    - Concerning JRA, 1906-1950 (Box 1)
    - James B. Angell to James O. Murray, 1859-1904 (Box 1)
    - Agnes Sack to "My Friend" [JRA?], 1872-1904 (Box 1)
  - Committees
    - National Academy of Sciences - Committee on Memorials, 1920-1935 (Box 1)
    - Extract from Minutes of the Board of Directors - National Broadcasting Co. [2 copies], 1948 April 2 (Box 1)
    - Report of the Committee on Numbers and Scholarship, 1903 April (Box 1)
    - Teaching Films Custodian, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
    - War Department Advisory Board, 1920-1929 (Box 1)
  - Angell Exhibit, 1951 November 5 - 1952 January 24 (Box 1)
  - Catalogue of Alexis Caswell's Library, 1833 August (Box 1)
  - Certificates, 1868 (Box 1)
  - Cost Projections sent to Mr. Harkness, 1929 December 19 (Box 1)
  - Legal Documents, 1901-1935 (Box 1)
  - Memorandum on the Division of Budgets, 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1897, undated (Box 1)
  - Press Releases, 1949 March 4 (Box 1)
  - Receipts, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - Printed matter, 1908-1950 (Box 1)
  - Reprints, 1902-1917 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Speeches, addresses, 1921-1950, undated (Box 1)
    - Autobiographical manuscript, undated (Box 1)
    - The Early Problems of the Yale Medical School - by JRA, 1949 February 5 (Box 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Psychological monographs, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified writings, undated (Box 1)
    - Virtues and Shortcomings of American School, Particularly Secondary Schools, undated (Box 1)
    - Yerkes, Robert M. Memorandum on the Relations of Research to Teaching, 1921 June 25 (Box 1)
  - Framed Picture of H.H. K'ung, undated (Box 2)
- Additional Material, 1986; Accession 1987-M-069
  - "The Angells Speak", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Katharine and James Angell from Norman Cousins, Brendan Gill, and Robert Yerkes, 1944-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 1944-1962; Accession 2005-M-087
  See Accession 1987-M-069, Box 1, folder 2